Finding Aid for the Edouard Roditi Papers LSC.0644
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Printed material by or about Édouard Roditi.
  - Erinnerungen an Musil by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 80)
    Series Title: NEUE DEUTSCHE HEFTE
    no. 90, (November / December 1962), p. 27-35.
    Edited by Joachim Guenther. Published by Sigbert Mohn Verlag.
  - Letter from Bucharest by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 80)
    vol. 37, no. 7 (April 1974), p. 47-53.
  - Letter from Copenhagen by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 80)
    (March 1976), p. 32-35.
  - Letter from Teheran by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 80)
    vol. 37, no. 8 (May / June 1974), p. 60-66.
  - Letters from a lost Latin empire by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 80)
    Series Title: SUMAC
    vol. 3, no. 3 (Spring 1971), p. 44-47.
  - Poems [Untitled] by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 80)
    Translated by Miroslav Milovivch and Aleksander Majgebauer.
  - Report from Paris by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 80)
    vol. 39, no. 5 (February 1976), p. 24-26.
  - Report from Paris by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 80)
    vol. 37, no. 2 (November 1973), p. 24-27.
  - Report from Paris by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 80)
    vol. 37, no. 3 (December 1973), p. 24-29.
  - Report from Paris by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 80)
    vol. 37, no. 4 (January 1974), p. 18-23.
  - Report from Paris by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 80)
    vol. 37, no. 5 (February 1974), p. 20-25.
  - Report from Paris by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 80)
    (April 1975), p. 18-23.
  - Report from Paris by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 80)
    (March 1976), p. 28-31.
  - Report from Paris by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 80)
    vol. 39, no. 8 (May / June 1976), p. 26-30.
  - Report from Paris by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 80)
    (January 1978), p. 22-25.
  - Report from Paris by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 80)
    vol. 40, no. 2 (November / December 1976), p. 29-33.
  - Report from Paris by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 80)
    (October 1976), p. 28-31.
  - Report from Paris by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 80)
    (December 1974), p. 20-26.
  - I fantasmi erotici di Modesto Roldan by Roldan, Modesto. (Box 80)
    Rome: Carte Secrete [1973].
    "Roldan: Una geographica de la sensualidad" by Edouard Roditi, p. 13-15.
  - INSEL ALMANACH. (Box 81)
    Frankfurt: Insel Verlag, 1963.
    "Weinen um nicht zu lachen: Die Wiederentdeckung von Ambrose Bierce" by Edouard Roditi, p. 100-109.
  - Trente-cinq jeunes poetes Americains by Bosquet, Alain, ed. (Box 81)
    Paris: Gallimard [c1960].
    "The night prayer of Glueckel Hameln" and "The identity of contraries" by Edouard Roditi, p. 122-127, English text and French translations.
  - Oscar Wilde: a collection of critical essays by Ellman, Richard, ed. (Box 81)
    Cliffs, N.J.: Prentice-Hall, c1979.
    "Fiction as allegory: THE PICTURE OF DORIAN GRAY" by Edouard Roditi, p. 47-55.
  - Edouard Roditi - cultural ambassador by Goodman, Paul, et al. (Box 81)
    Reprint from THE LITERARY REVIEW, Vol. 3, no. 3 (Spring 1980), p. [430]-437.
  - Edouard Roditi - cultural ambassador by Goodman, Paul, et al. (Box 81)
    THE LITERARY REVIEW, Vol. 3, no. 3 (Spring 1960), p. [430]-437.
  - New Directions in prose and poetry 37 by Laughlin, James, ed. (Box 81)
    NEW DIRECTIONS ANNUAL. [New York: New Directions Publishing Corporation, c1978.] "Women to her midget lover" by Edouard Roditi, p. 1-9.
  - An American Jewish poet by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 81)
    Review of THE WRONG ANGEL by Stanley Moss in JUDAISM, vol. 16, no. 3 (Summer 1967), p. 381-384.
  - Aphorisms by Edouard Roditi by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 81)
    Reprint from THE LITERARY REVIEW, vol. 3, no. 3 (Spring 1960), p. [422]-429.
  - Aphorisms by Edouard Roditi by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 81)
    THE LITERARY REVIEW, vol. 3, no. 3 (Spring 1960), p. [422]-429.
  - Chagall's windows by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 81)
    COMMENTARY, vol. 33, no. 2 (February 1962), p. 152-154.
  - The Chicago manuscript of the Castillian Breviario de Amor by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 81)
    Reprint from MODERN PHILOLOGY, vol. 45, no.1 (August 1947), p. 15-22.
  - Cold war bulletins by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 81)
    KAYAK, no. 11 (1967), p. 46-47.
  - For Alice Nikitina by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 81)
    PAGANY, vol. 1, no. 4 (Fall 1930), p. 17-18.
  - From the lower depths by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 81)
    Review of books dealing with German concentration camps from COMMENTARY, vol. 25, no. 1 (January 1958), p. 80-83.
  - G.A. Borgese by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 81)
    Reprint from THE SEWANEE REVIEW (January 1942), p. 1-12.
  - The genesis of neoclassical tragedy by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 81)
    Reprint from THE SOUTH ATLANTIC QUARTERLY, vol. 46, no. 1 (January 1947), p. [93]-108.
  - The genesis of neoclassical tragedy by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 81)
    THE SOUTH ATLANTIC QUARTERLY, vol. 46, no. 1 (January 1947), p. [93]-108.
  - The growth and structure of Croce's philosophy by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 81)
    JOURNAL OF AESTHETICS AND ART CRITICISM, no. 5 (Spring 1942), p. 14-29.
  - Kronika kulturalna, List z Diaspory by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 81)
    Polish translation of article on Estonian exile literature from KULTURA, no. 11/37 (November 1950), p. 66-70.
  - El lamento de Leon Hebreo by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 81)
    Introduction and translation by Amadeo Sole-Leris. Offprint from PAPELES DE SON ARMADANS, no. 72 (March 1962), p. [281]-293.
  - The paths of prayer by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 81)
    THE JEWISH QUARTERLY, vol. 21, no. 1/2 (1973), p. 215-216.
  - Poems by Edouard Roditi by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 81)
    THE LITERARY REVIEW, vol. 3, no. 3 (Spring 1960), p. [416]-421. "The spell," "Confessions of a nebbich," "World without end," Stanzas to a barbarian slave," "Burgenstock:, Letter to Kenneth Rexroth," "Alter ego."
  - Poems by Edouard Roditi by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 81)
    Reprint from THE LITERARY REVIEW, vol. 3, no. 3 (Spring 1960), p. [416]-421. "The spell," "Confessions of a nebbich," "World without end," Stanzas to a barbarian slave," "Burgenstock," "Letter to Kenneth Rexroth," "Alter ego."
  - Problemas no estudo de lingua e da literatura Ladinas by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 81)
    OCIDENTE, vol. 83, no. [ ] (1972), p. [3]-12.
  - Recent Jewish writings in France by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 81)
    JUDAISM, vol. 16, no. 4 (Fall 1967), p. 485-489.
  - A Sephardic family by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 81)
    COMMENTARY, vol. 29, no. 2 (February 1960), p. 133-140.
  - Siir ve Sair by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 81)
    YENI UFUKLAR, (1960), p. 258-259.
  - La sultana de los desmazalados by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 81)
    PAPELES DE SON ARMADANS no. 161 (August 1969), p. [151]-162. Translation by Amadeo Sole-Leris.
  - Sur quelques problemes que posent encore les recits des survivants de l'expedition de Magellan by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 81)
    OCIDENTE vol. 76, no. 373 (May 1969), p. 219-221.
  - Os verdadeiros grandes by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 81)
    OCIDENTE vol. 81, no. 404 (December 1971), p. 353-359.
  - The wisdom and folly of Edward Benlowes by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 81)
    COMPARATIVE LITERATURE vol. 2, no. 4 (Fall 1950), p. [343]-353. Reprint.
  - The writing on the wall: Jewish life in modern France by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 81)
    COMMENTARY vol. 26, no. 1 (July 1958), p. 66-69.
  - Genesis rejuvenated by Suares, Carlo. (Box 81)
    London: The Menard Press, 1973. Translated from the French by Edouard Roditi.
  - A telephone - but no visa. (Box 82)
    Report on Roditi's expulsion from France from DISSENT vol. 5, no. 3 (Summer 1958), p. 296-[297].
  - Artificial paradise: on hashish and wine as means of expanding individuality by Baudelaire, Charles. (Box 82)
    New York: Herder and Herder [c 1971]. Foreword by Edouard Roditi, p. vii-xxii.
  - Surrealismus by Bosquet, Alain, ed. (Box 82)
    Berlin: Karl H. Henssel Verlag [1950].
  - Les plus belles lettres de Delacroix by Delacroix, Eugene. (Box 82)
    Paris: Calmann-Levy [c 1963]. Introduction and selection by Edouard Roditi.
  - La princesse artificielle; Mon piaffeur noir by Firbank, Ronald. (Box 82)
    Paris: Gallimard [1937]. MON PIAFFEUR NOIR translated from the English by Edouard Roditi.
  - Oxford poetry, 1929 by MacNeice, Louis, and Spender, Stephen, ed. (Box 82)
    Oxford: Basil Blackwell, 1929.
  - Des Africains et des Europeens by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 82)
    Clipping from LA REVUE DE PARIS (December 1964), p. 141-142.
  - The Boulissa's pilgrimage by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 82)
    THE LITERARY REVIEW vol. 11, no. 1 (Autumn 1967), p. 39-45.
  - Byzance, son art et ses frontieres by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 82)
    Clipping from LA REVUE DE PARIS (August/September 1964), p. 149-151.
  - Cavaliers apocalyptiques by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 82)
    Clipping from LA REVUE DE PARIS (October 1964), p. [76]-81.
  - Chagall's early years by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 82)
    Clipping from ENCOUNTER no. 54 (March 1958), p. 46-53.
  - Chapiro in Montparnasse by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 82)
    Clipping from WORLD JEWRY (March 1961), p. 15.
  - The complaint of Jehuda Abravanel by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 82)
    THE JEWISH REVIEW no. 7 (December / March 1934), p. 93-95.
  - High camp in Japanese poetry by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 82)
    Clipping from LONDON MAGAZINE (October 1969), p. 74-79.
  - An interview with Ghika by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 82)
    THE CHARIOTEER vol. 1, no. 2 (Autumn 1960), p. 50-62.
  - Israel through German eyes by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 82)
    Clipping from WORLD JEWRY (July/August 1959), p. 3.
  - Lorsque tout est fini by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 82)
    CAHIERS DE L'ETOILE vol. 3, no. 16 (July/August 1930), p. 571-574.
  - Master of ceremonies by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 82)
    Clipping from WORLD JEWRY vol. 1, no. 10 (December 1958), p. 22.
  - A new exodus: Algerian Jews in France by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 82)
    Clipping from JUDAISM (Winter 1963), p. [101]-106.
  - Poem [untitled] by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 82)
    THE ADELPHI vol. 3, no. 3 (December 1931), p. 161.
  - Poems, 1928-1948 by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 82)
    Norfolk, Conn.: New Directions Books [c 1949].
  - Portrait of alias, or the real life of Maurice Sachs by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 82)
    PROSE no. 9 (Fall 1974), p. 135-157.
  - A revolution in synagogue architecture by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 82)
    Clipping from WORLD JEWRY vol. 1, no. 7 (September 1958), p. 20-24.
  - Die Tuerkische Literatur in Westlicher Sicht by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 82)
    NEUE DEUTSCHE HEFTE (n.d.), p. 87-89. Reprint.
  - Variations on the theme of celestial harmony by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 82)
    ARTS IN SOCIETY vol. 4, no. 3 (Fall/Winter 1967), p. 539-545. Regarding the Mevlevi dervishes.
  - What is a Jew? by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 82)
    Clipping from ENCOUNTER (October 1965), p. 91-92.
  - Die Geschichte meines Bruders by Siemsen, Hans. (Box 82)
    Berlin & Leipzig: Deutsche Verlags & Anstalt Stuttgart, 1923. Original German text. Roditi translated this into French for EUROPE, vol. 39, no. 154 (October 15, 1935).
  - L' histoire de mon frere by Siemsen, Hans. (Box 82)
    EUROPE vol. 39, no. 154 (October 15, 1935), p. [153]-178. French translation by Edouard Roditi.
  - Oxford poetry, 1929 by Spender, Stephen and MacNeice, Louis, ed. (Box 82)
    Oxford: Basil Blackwell, 1929. "Poem, for Mrs. Tindall" and "Hand" by Edouard Roditi, p. 33-34.
  - Form ohne Sinn? by Boylan, Terence, pseud. (Box 83)
    Clipping from DER MONAT no. 14 (1949), p. 213-214.
  - Letter to the editor by Huelsenbeck, Richard, et al. (Box 83)
    Clipping from DER MONAT no. [ ], 1959-1960, p. 94-95. Letters concerning Roditi's article, "Hannah Hoech und die Berliner Dadaisten," DER MONAT, no. 134 (November 1959).
  - The letters of Sebastian Schirlewahn by Koval, Alexander. (Box 83)
    UNIVERSITY OF KANSAS CITY REVIEW (Summer 1951), p. [337]-347.
  - anthologies as balance sheets by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 83)
    Clipping from POETRY: A MAGAZINE OF VERSE vol. 56, no. 4 (July 1940), p. 225-228. Review of ANTHOLOGIE DES POETES DE LA N.R.F.
  - Art and scholarship by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 83)
    Clipping from COMMENTARY (November 1971), p. 86, 90-99. Reviews of JEWISH CEREMONIAL ART AND RELIGIOUS OBSERVANCES by Abram Kanoff, and THE HORNED MOSES IN MEDIEVAL ART AND THOUGHT by Ruth Millinkoff.
  - Art in film by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 83)
    Clipping from THE NEW LEADER (October 14, 1963), p. 30-31.
  - The art of Wilde's criticism by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 83)
    Clipping from CHIMERA vol. 4, no. 2 (Winter 1946), p. 5-16.
  - Axis siren-songs by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 83)
    Clipping from DECISION vol. 3, no. 1/2 (January / February 1942), p. 66-69.
  - Baudelaire without tears by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 83)
    Clipping from POETRY: A MAGAZINE OF VERSE vol. 66, no. 1 (April 1945), p. 48-51. Review of BAUDELAIRE, A CRITICISM by Joseph D. Bennett.
  - Bertold Brecht by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 83)
    Clipping from DER MONAT no. 98 (November 1956), p. 85-88.
  - Book review - [Regarding Brazil] by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 83)
    Clipping from THE INTER-AMERICAN QUARTERLY (July 1941), p. [112]-116. Review of DIARIO INTIMO DO ENGENHEIRO VAUTHIER, UM ENGENHEIRO FRANCES NO BRAZIL, ASSIMILACAO DE POPULACOES MARGINAIS NO BRASIL, ENSAIOS BRASILIANOS.
  - Braque and the tests of time by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 83)
    Clipping from THE NEW LEADER (November 11, 1963), p. 29-30.
  - Carta da Turquia by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 83)
    Clipping from COLOQUIO no. 16 (December 1961), p. 45-[47].
  - Cosima Tura by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 83)
    Clipping from ART NEWS AND REVIEW (June 7, 1958). Clipping.
  - The critic as baby-sitter by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 83)
    Clipping from ARTS MAGAZINE (November 1963), p. 48-51, 73.
  - Crumbs from Camus' table by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 83)
    Clipping from THE NEW LEADER (October 28, 1963), p. 22-24.
  - Culture, communism and fascism by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 83)
    Clipping from THE TWENTIETH CENTURY vol. 4, no. 22 (December 1932), p. 2-4.
  - A curious mass conversion by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 83)
    Clipping from COMMENTARY (September 1957), p. 275-277. Review of SAN NICANDRO, HISTOIRE D'UNE CONVERSION by Elena Cassin.
  - Delacroix's legacy by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 83)
    Clipping from THE NEW LEADER (August 19, 1963), p. 24-25.
  - ESTUDIOS DE SOCIOLOGIA VENEZOLANA; EL HOMBRE Y LA HISTORIA Y OTROS ENSAYS [book review] by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 83)
    Clipping from THE INTER-AMERICAN QUARTERLY vol. 3, no. 4 (October 1941), p. 140-142. Review of ESTUDIOS DE SOCIOLOGIA VENEZOLANA by Pedro M. Arcaya and EL HOMBRE Y LA HISTORIA Y OTROS ENSAYS by Jose Gil Fortoul.
  - Der Fall Ezra Pound by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 83)
    Clipping from DER MONAT no. 10 (July 1949), p. [107]-113.
  - The fate of Otto Freundlich: painter 'Maudit' by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 83)
    Clipping from COMMENTARY (September 1955), p. 248-254.
  - A Faust-fight by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 83)
    Clipping from POETRY: A MAGAZINE OF VERSE vol. 61, no. 1 (October 1942), p. 406-408. Reviews of GOETHE'S FAUST, translated by C.F. MacIntyre, and FAUST: PARTS ONE AND TWO, translated by George Madison Priest.
  - Felix Fabian: Memories of the Shtetl by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 83)
    JEWISH CHRONICLE LITERARY SUPPLEMENT (June 20, 1969), p. iv-v.
  - Four poems by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 83)
    Clipping from POETRY: A MAGAZINE OF VERSE vol. 56, no. 3 (June 1940), p. 121-123. Titles: The political prisoner, John Lack-land, London by moonlight, Amare est amarum.
  - A French poet and his English critics by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 83)
    Clipping from THE SEWANEE REVIEW (Winter 1944), p. [102]-117.
  - Gemaelde, Sammler, Preise by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 83)
    Clipping from DER MONAT (n.d.), p. 48-50.
  - Gibt es eine Neger-Lyrik? by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 83)
    Clipping from DER MONAT no. 2 (1948), p. [102-107].
  - A gothic Parthenon by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 83)
    POETRY: A MAGAZINE OF VERSE vol. 58, no. 5 (August 1941), p. 278-280. Review of ANTHOLOGY OF THE PROVENCAL TROUBADOURS, edited by Raymond Thompson Hill and Thomas Goddard Bergin.
  - Hommage a Lyonel Feininger by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 83)
    Clipping from PRISME no. 2 (April 15, 1956), p. 32-[33].
  - In a silver sea by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 83)
    Clipping from POETRY: A MAGAZINE OF VERSE vol. 60, no. 4 (July 1942), p. 225-227. Review of POEMS by F.T. Prince and THE BURIED STREAM, COLLECTED POEMS 1908-1940 by Geoffrey Faber.
  - In praise of Erasmus by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 83)
    Clipping from THE NEW LEADER (June 23, 1969), p. 19-20.
  - Introduction a la peinture Turque de notre temps by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 83)
    COLOQUIO no. 28 (April 1964), p. 35-40.
  - The Jew in recent Franco-Jewish novels: assimilation and the rights of man by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 83)
    Clipping from COMMENTARY (November 1956), p. 442-446.
  - Jewish artists among the Dutch romantics by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 83)
    Clipping from LE JUDAISME SEPHARDI no. 14 (May 1957), p. 632-636.
  - Jewish writers and the Jewish experience by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 83)
    Clipping from CONGRESS BI-WEEKLY vol. 36, no. 8 (May 26, 1969), p. 18-20. Review of AFTER THE TRADITIONS: ESSAYS ON MODERN JEWISH WRITING by Robert Alter.
  - Jews of the Maghreb by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 83)
    Clipping from THE JEWISH CHRONICLE (April 4, 1969), p. [ ].
  - Joachim Karsch (1897-1945) by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 83)
    Clipping from THE PAINTER & SCULPTOR vol. 3, no. 4 (Winter 1960/61), p. 1-4.
  - Lament by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 83)
    Clipping from POETRY: A MAGAZINE OF VERSE vol. 54, no. 1 (April 1939), p. 8-9.
  - Der Leidensweg der Berliner Museen by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 83)
    Clipping from DER MONAT nos. 8/9 (June 1949), p. [141]-145.
  - Letter [] by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 83)
    Clipping from POETRY: A MAGAZINE OF VERSE vol. 67, no. 3 (December 1945), p. 173.
  - Letter from Lisbon by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 83)
    Clipping from THE NEW LEADER (November 12, 1962), p. 12-14.
  - Letter from Paris by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 83)
    Clipping from THE NEW LEADER (April 29, 1963), p. 30- incomplete.
  - Letter from West Berlin by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 83)
    Clipping from THE NEW LEADER (September 3, 1962), p. 24-25.
  - Lipschitz by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 83)
    Clipping from ART NEWS AND REVIEW (January 31, 1959), p. 14.
  - Londres, ou le brouillard insolite by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 83)
    Clipping from LES PARISIENS no. 3 (April 1961), p. [16]-19, 67.
  - MAIDEN VOYAGE by Denton Welch [book review] by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 83)
    TOMORROW (May 1945), p. 66-67.
  - Marc Chagall: Unterhaltungen mit der Kuenstler by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 83)
    Clipping from DER MONAT no. 113 (February 1958), p. [33]-47.
  - The marquise who wasn't a lady by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 83)
    Clipping from THE NEW LEADER (October 15, 1962), p. 24-[25].
  - Mediteration sur une terrasse by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 83)
    LES PARISIENS no. 2 (February / March 1961), p. 60-61.
  - Ein Mittagessen mit Max Ernst by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 83)
    Clipping from DER MONAT no. 150 (March 1961), p. [64]-73. With inscription to Roditi from Ernst.
  - New American painting by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 83)
    Clipping from ART NEWS AND REVIEW (August 16, 1958), p. 6.
  - Le nez en l'air a Barcelone by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 83)
    LES PARISIENS (December 1960), p. 49-60.
  - North African Jews by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 83)
    Clipping from THE MENORAH JOURNAL (Spring/Summer 1955), p. 72-86.
  - North Africa's great migration by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 83)
    Clipping from THE NEW LEADER (September 28, 1964), p. 8-9.
  - Novel of the triply divided Jew: Alfred Memmi's STATUE OF SALT by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 83)
    COMMENTARY (April 1955), p. 380-385.
  - The novels of post-war Germany by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 83)
    Clipping from UNIVERSITY OF KANSAS CITY REVIEW (Spring 1951), p. [220]-230.
  - Oliver Wendell Holmes as novelist by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 83)
    Clipping from ARIZONA QUARTERLY vol. 1, no. 1 (Winter 1945), p. [23]-33.
  - On aesthetics by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 83)
    Clipping from UNIVERSITY OF KANSAS CITY REVIEW (Winter 1944), p. [147]-153.
  - Oscar Wilde and Henry James by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 83)
    Clipping from UNIVERSITY OF KANSAS CITY REVIEW (Autumn 1948), p. [52]-56.
  - The peaceful invasion by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 83)
    Clipping from THE NEW LEADER (October 12, 1964), p. 13-15.
  - La peinture d'Eduardo Luis by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 83)
    Clipping from COLOQUIO (n.d.), p. [ ], 32-36.
  - Pferde, Reiter und die Katastrophe by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 83)
    Clipping from DER MONAT no. 127 (April 1959), p. [68]-72.
  - Playing the market by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 83)
    Clipping from THE NEW LEADER (July 8, 1963), p. 23-24.
  - Poem for L by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 83)
    Clipping from POETRY (December 20, 1946), p. 14.
  - The poet: Magician or mountebank by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 83)
    Series Title: HEMISPHERES
    vol. 2, no. 5 (Spring 1945), p. 69-72.
  - Poetry and geography by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 83)
    Series Title: POETRY: A MAGAZINE OF VERSE
    vol. 62, no. 4 (July 1943), p. 231-233.
    Review of AN ANTHOLOGY OF CONTEMPORARY LATIN AMERICAN POETRY, edited by Dudley Fitts. Clipping.
  - Poetry, mysticism, and magic by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 83)
    vol. 53, no. 4 (January 1939), p. 218-223.
    Review of L'EXPERIENCE POETIQUE by Rolland de Reneville and SITUATION DE LA POESIE by Jacques and Raissa Maritain. Clipping.
  - The return of Europe's Jews by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 83)
    Series Title: COMMENTARY
    (July 1963), p. 63-68.
    The "return" of Europe's Jews. Clipping.
  - The romantic landscape painters of America by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 83)
    Series Title: UNIVERSITY OF KANSAS CITY REVIEW
    (Autumn 1950), p. [47]-51.
  - Signac revalued by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 83)
    Series Title: APOLLO
    (March 1964), p. 240-241.
  - The still voice of German poetry by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 83)
    (1946), p. 208-220.
    With holograph corrections by Roditi. Clipping.
  - Surpluses and supermarkets by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 83)
    Series Title: THE NEW LEADER
    (December 23, 1963), p. 16-17.
  - Surrealism serves the state by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 83)
    vol. 68, no. 1 (April 1946), p. 54-56.
    Review of ODE TO BOMBED LONDON by Philippe Soupault with English translations by Norman Cameron.
    Also reviewed: THREE PRAYERS FOR PILOTS by Jules Roy, French text and English version by George Ellidge. Clipping.
  - T.S. Eliot: Persoenlichkeit und Werk by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 83)
    Series Title: DER MONAT
    no. 3 (1948), p. [51]-59.
  - TALH by Jeremy Ingalls [book review] by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 83)
    Series Title: ARIZONA QUARTERLY
    vol. 1, no. 3 (Autumn 1945), p. 86-89.
  - TEACHER IN AMERICA by Jacques Barzun [book review] by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 83)
    Series Title: TOMORROW
    (May 1945), p. 66-67.
  - Translations of Rimbaud and Lorca by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 83)
    vol. 63, no. 11 (November 1943), p. 96-98.
    Review of SELECTED VERSE POEMS OF ARTHUR RIMBAUD, translated by Norman Cameron.
    Also reviewed, SELECTED POEMS OF FEDERICO GARCIA LORCA translated by Stephen Spender and J.L. Lili. Clipping.
  - Translator's dilemma by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 83)
    vol. 67, no. 5 (February 1946), p. 278-282.
    Review of A SEASON IN HELL by Arthur Rimbaud, translated by Louise Varese. Clipping.
  - Treblinka: the shocking view by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 83)
    Series Title: CONGRESS BI-WEEKLY
    (n.d.), p. 24-25.
  - Two poems by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 83)
    vol. 61, no. 6 (March 1943), p., 656-658.
    "Cassandra's dream" and "The plots". Clipping.
  - The unspoken word by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 83)
    vol. 63, no. 1 (October 1943), p. 48-50.
    Review of NEW POEMS by Dylan Thomas. Clipping.
  - WILFRID OWENS: POEMS with notes by Edmund Blunden [book review] by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 83)
    (March 195), p. 60.
  - The world of Marc Chagall by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 83)
    Series Title: JEWISH CHRONICLE LITERARY SUPPLEMENT
    (December 13, 1968), p. iv-v.